我知道你这个表情
I know that look.
你一有事就沉默
Then you get really quiet.
要跟我说说吗
So, are you gonna tell me?
今早我们吵了一架
We had a fight this morning.
吵的很凶  很伤人
It got ugly, hurtful.
很遗憾  亲爱的  男人有时就是混蛋
I'm sorry, hon-- Men can be jerks.
问题是  如果让我说实话
Thing is, if we're being honest,
混蛋的人不是他
he wasn't the asshole.
明白了
Ah, got ya.
他不过是努力的想理性点
He was trying so hard to be reasonable.
但这让我更生气
It just pushed my buttons all the more.
老天  有时我真希望他能和我大吵一架
God, I sometimes wish he would just have it out with me...
发发脾气
and blow up,
骂我是个婊子也行  如果我真是那样的话
tell me I'm being a bitch, if that's what I'm being.
相反  他只是
Instead, he's just so...
-不要责怪自己了  -不要吗
- Don't beat yourself up. - No?
就因为自己的丈夫不冲自己发火
You can't tell me that being pissed at your husband
就生他的气
because he doesn't yell at you
这一点都说不通吧
is even close to being rational.
我和汤姆倒是没这个问题
That's one problem I don't have with Tom.
但是你还爱他
But you still love him.
对  我爱他  最好是这样
Sure, I do-- might as well.
-我俩随遇而安  -你们这么务实  我很欣赏
- We're lifers. - I admire your pragmatism.
你还爱瑞克吗
You still love Rick?
我问过自己很多次
I've been asking myself that a lot,
我想是的
and-and I-I think the answer's "Yes."
只不过我在努力找回那种感觉
It's just, I'm trying to remember how that works.
也许唯一的真正的问题在于
Maybe the only real problem we have
我们结婚的时候太年轻了
is we got married so young.
这
It's--
失陪一下
Excuse me.
他还活着吧
Is he alive?
正在手术中
He's in surgery.
怎么回事
How?
总线告诉我们说
There was a radio call that said
车里有两个嫌疑犯
that there was two suspects in a car,
但其实还有一个人
but there was a third man.
有人把事情搞砸了
Somebody screwed up.
我也搞砸了
I screwed up.
我没及时看到那个人  洛莉  都是我的错
I ju-- I did not see him in time-- Lori, it's my fault.
我不相信
I-I don't believe that.
我应该和他说什么
What do I say?
我怎么告诉我儿子他爸中枪了
How do I tell my son his father's been shot?
你不用一个人去说
You don't have to do it alone.
好吧
Okay.
《行尸走肉》
快走  蠢货
Hey, you move, shithead.
-快带我们过去  -还有多远
-Come on, get us there! - How far?
-多远  -还有半里地
- How far? - Another half mile,
那个方向
That way!
赫谢尔  去找赫谢尔  他会救你儿子的
Hershel, talk to Hershel-- He'll help your boy.
-对不起  -我们走  快点
- I'm sorry. - Let's go. Come on!
爸爸
Dad!
就到了
Come on.
-他被咬了吗  -中枪了  你的人干的
- Was he bit? - Shot, by your man.
-奥蒂斯  -他说让我找赫谢尔
- Otis? - He said find Hershel.
你就是吗
Is that you?
帮帮我  救救我儿子
Help me-- Help my boy.
把他抱进去  快进屋
Get him inside-- inside!
帕特里夏  把全套工具拿来
Patricia, I need my full kit.
-玛姬  -我在
- Maggie-- - Yeah?
止痛药  凝血剂  全拿过来
Painkillers, coagulates-- Grab everything.
干净的毛巾  床单  酒精
Clean towels, sheets, alcohol.
放在这
In here.
-枕套拿来  -他还活着吗
- Pillowcase. - Is-is he alive?
快点把枕套拿过来
Pillowcase, quick.
他还活着吗
Is-is he alive?
把枕套折起来  折成块
Fold it. Make a pad.
按住伤口
Put pressure on the wound.
还有心跳  但是很弱
I've got a heartbeat. It's faint.
我来按  你退后
I got it. Step back.
-玛姬  输液管  -我们需要地方
- Maggie, iv. - We need some space.
-你叫什么  -瑞克
- Your name? - R-rick.
-瑞克  -我我我是瑞克
- Rick? - I'm-I'm-I'm rick.
瑞克  我们会尽我们所能  好吗
Rick, we're gonna do everything we can, okay?
你得给我们留点空间
You need to give us some room.
就是现在
Now.
快跑
Move!
他还活着吗
He's alive-- He's still alive?
好了
Okay.
没事了
It's okay.
你脸上沾了血  老兄
You got blood, man.
没事
Okay.
给我吧
I'll take it from you.
他在哪  他还好吗
Where is he? Is he okay?
你知道他的血型吗
You know his blood type?
A型阳性  和我一样
A-positive-- s-same as mine.
那太幸运了
That's fortunate.
别走太远  待会会需要你
Don't wander far. I'm gonna need you.
怎么回事
What happened?
我在猎鹿
I was tracking a buck.
子弹钻过鹿射中了他
Bullet went through it.
一下子就穿过去了
Went clean through.
鹿减慢了子弹的速度
The deer slowed the bullet down,
救了他一命
which certainly saved his life,
但是子弹完全穿过他的身体
but it did not go through clean.
而是碎成了几片
It broke up into pieces.
如果我能把子弹碎片拿出来
If I can get the bullet fragments out...
我觉得有六片
And I'm countin' six.
我根本没有看到他
I never saw him.
直到他摔倒在地上
Not until he was on the ground.
-洛莉知道吗  -不  她
- Lori doesn't know? - No, she--
我妻子不知道  她还不知道
My wife doesn't know. My wife doesn't know.
你还在担心吗
You still worrying about it?
-有一声枪响  -我们都听到了
- It was a gunshot. - We all heard it.
为什么就一声  为何只开了一枪
Why one-- why just one gunshot?
也许他们击毙一个行尸
Maybe they took down a walker.
别敷衍我
Please don't patronize me.
你明知道瑞克或肖恩
You know Rck wouldn't risk a gunshot
绝不会为了打倒一个行尸而冒险开枪的
to put down one walker, or Shane.
他们会不出声地干掉它
They'd do it quietly.
他们现在是不是该赶上我们了
Shouldn't they have caught up with us by now?
不管怎么样  我们都无能为力
There's nothing we can do about it, anyway.
总不能听着回音在林子里乱转悠
Can't run around these woods chasing echoes.
-那我们现在怎么办  -按原计划行事
- So, what do we do? - Same as we've been.
继续去灌木丛找索菲亚
Beat the bush for Sophia,
想办法回到高速公路上
work our way back to the highway.
我相信他们能在房车那儿跟我们会合的
I'm sure they'll hook up with us back at the rv.
对你所经历的一切我感到很遗憾
I'm sorry for what you're going through.
我能理解你的感受
I know how you feel.
我想你确实懂  谢谢你
I suppose you do-- thank you.
一想到她  孤零零地一个人在外面
The thought of her, out here by herself...
不清楚的她情况  简直让我生不如死
It's the not knowing that's killin' me.
我不断盼望和祈祷她的结局别和艾米一样
I just keep hopin' and prayin' she doesn't wind up like Amy.
我的上帝
Oh, god!
这是我说过的最糟糕的话了
That's the worst thing I ever said.
我们都在跟你一起盼望和祈祷
We're all hoping and praying with you,
祈祷那些值得寄予希望的事
for what it's worth.
我告诉你什么值得祈祷吧
I'll tell ya what it's worth--
没一件狗屁事值得
Not a damn thing.
期盼和祷告都是浪费时间
It's a waste of time, all this hopin' and prayin'.
我们会找到那小女孩的下落
We're gonna locate that little girl.
她一定会没事的
She's gonna be just fine.
我是这里唯一一个佛教徒吗
Am I the only one zen around here?
我的天啊
Good lord.
告诉你吧  我们将会有一大堆零件
We are gonna have quite a collection of spare parts,
可以收集起来
I tell ya.
他们现在不是应该回来了吗
Shouldn't they be back by now?
天还没黑
It's still light.
现在还不用担心
Let's not worry, just yet.
你感觉好点没
How are you feelin'?
T仔
T-dog?
我刚刚问你  感觉怎么样
I asked you how you were feeling just now.
别避而不答
Please don't blow that question off.
真的很痛很痛
It really, really hurts.
跳着疼得厉害
It's throbbing something awful.
让我瞧瞧
Oh, let me see.
别...别碰它
Ah, don't-don't touch it!
对不起  真抱歉
I'm sorry-- I'm sorry.
听我说  你的静脉严重充血
Listen, your veins are very discolored.
你的伤口感染了
You got a hell of an infection there.
你可能因为血液中毒导致死亡
You could die from blood poisoning.
得了  伙计
Oh, man.
不就该这样吗
Wouldn't that be the way?
世界变成了地狱...
World gone to hell...
行尸崛起  侵食活人
The dead risen up to eat the living...
西奥多·道格拉斯死于他手臂上的小伤口
And Theodore Douglas gets done in by a cut on his arm.
这的确听起来太蠢了
Yeah, that would be-that would be stupid.
我昨天就说了
I-I've been saying since yesterday,
我们得给你弄点抗生素来
we gotta-we gotta get you some antibiotics.
我们一直在搜索这些车辆
We've been ransacking these cars the whole time.
我简直不敢相信这么大块地方都找不到
I can't believe that we have not found some ampicillin,
氨苄青霉素或什么别的药
or-or something in the-in the whole place.
-你信吗  -看上去这里应该有啊
- Can you? - Seems like there would be.
我也这么觉得
Well, that's what I think.
好吧
Well...
我们  我们找得还不彻底
We, uh, we haven't been thorough enough.
所以我们再找找吧
So, let's look some more.
为什么我当初让他跟我们一起来
Why'd I let him come with us?
我该让他跟着洛莉的
I should've sent him with Lori.
一旦你开始这么想
You know, you start that,
你就永远无法摆脱这阴影了
you never get that monkey off your back.
小姑娘失踪了  我去找不就得了
Little girl goes missing, you look for her.
简单明了
Simple.
你劝我说"到此为止  该回去了"
You said, "Call it-- head back."
我说什么不重要
Doesn't matter what I said.
卡尔遭到枪击是因为我不愿放弃
Carl got shot because I wouldn't cut bait.
躺在里面的本该是我
It should be me in there.
你以前经历过这些对吧  好搭档
You've been there, partner, right?
你挺过来了  他也行的
And you pulled through-- so will he.
这就是我从医院里出来的目的吗
Is that why I got outta that hospital?
找到我的家人后
Found my family for it
一切在这里结束  像现在这样
to end here, like this?
这算什么变态玩笑
This kind of s-sick joke?
不许再这样了
You stop it.
别这样
Just stop.
一个小姑娘失踪了
A little girl goes missing...
我去找不就得了  简单明了
You look for her-- it's plain and simple.
瑞克
Rick...
他需要输血
He needs blood.
你  按住他
You, hold him down.
-爸爸  -我按住他了
- Dad! - I got him.
马上就好了
Almost there.
住手  你会把他弄死的
Stop-- you're killin' him!
瑞克  你希望他活下来吗
Rick, do you want him to live?
-他需要输血  -快去输血
- He needs blood. - Do it now!
等等  等等
Wait-wait, hey.
他只是晕过去了
He just passed out.
取出一片
One down...
还剩五片
Five to go.
血压稳定
Pressure's stable.
洛莉得来这里
Lori needs to be here.
她都不知道发生什么事了
She doesn't even know what's goin' on.
我...我得去找她  带她回来
I got-I gotta go find her, bring her back.
-你不能那么做  -她是孩子的母亲
- You can't do that. - She's his mother!
她有权知道发生了什么事
She needs to know what's happened.
她儿子受了枪伤  躺在这里
Her son's lying here, shot.
可他还需要随时输血
And he's going to need more blood.
他50尺都走不了
He can't go more than 50 feet from this bed.
别担心
Hey, hey.
-我扶你  -我没事
- Come on. - I'm all right.
-我没事的  -我会陪他
- I'm all right. - I got him.
他暂时稳定了
He's stable, for now.
洛莉得来这里  肖恩  她必须要知道
Lori has to be here, shane-- she has to know.
好的  我懂
Okay, I get that.
我来处理这件事
I'm gonna handle it...
但你也得处理好你的事
But you've gotta handle your end.
我的事
My-my end?
你的任务是待在这  为了你儿子
Your end is being here, for your son.
即使他活下来了  不再需要你的血
Even if he didn't need your blood to survive,
我也不准你踏出这扇门一步
there is no way I'd ever let you walk out that door.
伙计  你敢试试我就打断你的腿
Man, I-I'd break your legs if you tried.
你懂我的意思  对吗
I mean, you know that, right?
如果他有什么事  你却不在这儿...
If something happened to him and you weren't here...
如果你不在的时候  他醒不过来了
If he slipped away while you were gone,
你永远都不会原谅自己的
you would never forgive yourself for that,
洛莉也不会原谅你的  兄弟
and neither would Lori, man.
你说得对
You're right.
我什么时候说错过
When was I ever wrong?
你知道吗
You know, when...
当你躺在医院里的时候
when you were in that hospital,
你最不应该离开的人是...
the one you were never supposed to leave, man...
你该看看洛莉当时的样子
you should've seen Lori.
她就像...
She was like--
她的坚强...
the strength of that woman...
你根本无法想象
you can't imagine it.
听着  这就是你现在该做的
See-see, that's what you gotta have now.
我的意思是  卡尔  他现在需要你
I mean, Carl, he needs that from you.
所以  你现在得打起精神  伙计
So, you wire yourself tight, my friend.
清楚了吗
You hear?
你来面对这个艰难的部分
You've got the hard part.
剩下的交给我就好
You just leave the rest to me, okay?
-好吗  -好
- All right. - All right.
他暂时脱离了危险
He's out of danger for the moment,
但我还得把剩下的子弹碎片取出来
But I need to remove those remaining fragments.
怎么取
How?
你也看见当时他那个样子了
You saw how he was.
我明白  但是刚才取出的是最浅的一个
I know, and that was the shallowest one.
还得再深入一点取出其它的
I need to go deeper to get the others.
-天呐  -还有更棘手的事
- Oh, man . - There's more.
说吧
Tell me.
他的腹部肿胀  血压下降
His belly's distended, his pressure's dropping,
这说明有内出血
which means there's internal bleeding.
肯定有块碎片割到了血管
A fragment must have nicked one of the blood vessels.
我得给他做手术  找到出血点然后缝合
I have to open him up, find the bleeder and stitch it.
在这过程中  他不能动
And he can't move while I'm in there.
我的意思是  必须纹丝不动
I mean, at all.
如果他还像之前那样
If he reacts the same as before,
我有可能会割到动脉
I'll sever an artery
那他在几分钟内就会死亡
and he'll be dead in minutes.
为了手术  我得让他麻醉昏迷
To even try this, I have to put him under.
但如果这么做
But if I do,
他就不能自己呼吸了
He won't be able to breathe on his own.
结果还是一样糟
Same bad results.
-那该怎么办  -你得找个呼吸器
- What'll it take? - You need a respirator.
-还有呢  -还有连接呼吸器的管子
- What else? - The tube that goes with it,
其他医用物品  手术被单  缝合线
extra surgical supplies, drapes, sutures.
如果这些都有的话  你能救好他吗
If you had all that, you could save him?
如果这些都有  我会尽力
If I had all that, I could try.
最近的医院一个月前失火了
Nearest hospital went up in flames a month ago.
-高中学校里有  -我也是这么想的
- The high school. - That's what I was thinkin'.
那里设了一个应急所
They set up a FEMA shelter there.
那儿应该有我们需要的所有东西
They would have everything we need.
我最后一次看到时那地方就已被行尸占据
Place was overrun last time I saw it.
根本没办法靠近  也许现在好些了
You couldn't get near it-- maybe it's better now.
我说过  剩下的任务交给我
I said, leave the rest to me.
现在收回这句话太晚了哈
Is it too late to take that back?
-我不想你只身前往  -行了
- I hate you goin' alone. - Come on.
医生  给我列个单子  画张地图吧
Doc, why don't you do me a list, draw me a map.
不需要地图了  我带你去
You won't need a map-- I'll take you there.
-只有五英里远  -奥蒂斯  不要
- Ain't but five miles. - Otis, no.
亲爱的  我们没时间玩猜谜游戏了
Honey, we don't have time for guesswork
我得负责任
and I'm responsible.
我不会在这坐视不管
I ain't gonna sit here while this fella
让他一个人去
takes this on alone.
-不会有事的  -你确定要这样吗
- I'll be all right. - Are you sure about this?
你知道他说的这些东西
Do you even know what any of the stuff
长什么样儿吗
he's talking about looks like?
我想想  还真不知道
Come to think, no.
我以前当过急诊志愿者
I've been a volunteer EMT.
我知道
I do.
我们可以一直在这儿讨论着
Now, we can talk about this 'till next Sunday,
或者赶紧速度去
or we could just go do it real quick.
那就赶紧去吧
I'll take right quick.
我该谢谢你
I should thank you.
等你儿子能活蹦乱跳了之后
Wait 'till that boy of yours is up and around,
再谈这个吧
Then we'll talk.
我去拿些东西
I'll gather some things.
你老婆  她在哪
Where is she-- your wife?
马上就要天黑了
We'll lose the light before too long.
-我觉得我们该撤了  -我们回去吧
- I think we should call it. - Let's head back.
我们明天继续找吗
We'll pick it up again tomorrow?
对  我们明天会找到她的
Yeah, we'll find her tomorrow.
拿到需要的东西之后马上离开
Just get what you need and get out of there.
坚强点  好吗
You stay strong, all right?
瑞克  这真是把好枪
That's a fine weapon, Rick.
我会把它完好无损地带回来
I'll bring it back in good shape.
这是我唯一一把枪
Only one I got.
今天真是诡异极了
Man, this turned into one strange day.
谁说不是呢
Didn't it, though?
我们去看看你儿子吧
Let's check on your boy.
我找到了些电池
Found some more batteries,
一瓶挺时髦的香水
a bottle of very trendy pink water,
一把全新的砍刀
an excellent new machete,
而且我觉得格伦说不定会喜欢这把吉他
and I thought Glenn might like this guitar.
也许他会弹
Maybe he plays.
没找到药
No drugs.
你呢
You?
对  找到点布洛芬和烟
Yeah, ibuprofen and these.
我们现在在干吗
What are we doin'?
把这些日用品集中放一起
Pullin' supplies together.
不  我是说
No, I mean...
我们在这儿要干什么
What are we doin'?
其他人都在树林里
People off in the woods,
在找那个可怜的小女孩  而我们却在这待着
They's looking for that poor girl and we're here.
为什么
Why?
因为他们认为咱俩最弱
'Cause they think we're the weakest.
你多大年纪了  七十岁么
What are you, 70?
六十四了
64.
而我是个黑人
And I'm the one black guy.
你明白我的处境多么朝不保夕吗
Realize how precarious that makes my situation?
你在说什么鬼话
What the hell are you talking about?
我说的是那两个老好人警官
I'm talking about two good-old-boy cowboy sheriffs
还有那个因为我把钥匙弄丢了
and a redneck whose brother cut off his own hand
所以他哥哥切断自己手腕的土包子
because I dropped a key.
你觉得我们这些人中
Who in that scenario you think
谁会先被干掉
is gonna be first to get lynched?
你开玩笑呢吧
You can't be serious.
我  我是不是错过什么了
Am I-- hey, am I missing something?
那些警察做啥都是为咱们好
Those cowboys have done all right by us.
而且如果我没说错的话
And if I'm not mistaken,
那个土包子不辞辛苦地替你收拾烂摊子
That redneck went out of his way
还不止一次
to save your ass-- more than once.
别忘了还有安德莉亚
And don't forget about Andrea.
她杀了亲妹妹
Kills her own sister.
她妹妹那时已经死了
She was already dead.
然后她还要自杀
Then wants to blow herself up.
是她没错  就是她没错
Yeah, she's all there.
当时她正经历艰难时刻
She's havin' a tough time.
你这人有毛病啊
What is wrong with you?
全世界都在经历艰难时刻
The whole world's havin' a tough time.
可恶  哥们  睁大眼
Damn, man! Open your eyes.
看看我们身处何方
Look where we are.
-困在这鬼地方  -小点声
- Stuck in this mess here! - Shh!
咱俩溜吧
Let's-- let's just go.
咱们把这房车开走
Let's just take the RV.
你已经走极端了
You've gone off the deep end.
我是认真的
I mean it, man.
咱们干嘛要坐在路边当活饵子
Why are we on the side of this road like live bait?
开路吧  就咱俩
Let's go, you and me.
趁他们还没回来
Let's go before they get back.
天哪
Oh, my god!
你发烧了
You're burnin' up.
药给我
Give me that.
快点儿
Come on.
来  吃药
Here, take these.
得让烧退了
We've got to knock that fever down.
他们跑到什么鬼地方去了
Where the hell are they?
还有多远
How much farther?
不远了
Not much...
像乌鸦一样飞  一百码左右就到了
Maybe a hundred yards as the crow flies.
可惜我们不是乌鸦
Too bad we're not crows.
"像乌鸦一样飞"  放屁
As the crow flies, my ass.
安德莉亚
Andrea?
不不  不
No, no. Oh, no!
你是洛莉吗
Lori?
你是洛莉·格兰姆斯吗
Lori Grimes?
我是洛莉
I'm Lori.
瑞克让我来的  你得马上跟我走
Rick sent me-- you've got to come now.
什么
What?
出了意外  卡尔中枪了
There's been an accident. Carl's been shot.
他还活着  但你得马上跟我走
He's still alive but you've gotta come now.
瑞克需要你  快来吧
Rick needs you-- just come!
等会儿  等会儿
Whoa-whoa-whoa!
我们又不认得这姑娘
We don't know this girl.
你不能上她的马
You can't get on that horse.
瑞克说你们有同伴在公路上
Rick said you had others on the highway.
在大塞车那儿  对吗
That big traffic snarl?
-是的  -折返到费尔伯恩路
- Uh-huh. - Backtrack to Fairburn Road.
走两里就是我们的农场
Two miles down is our farm.
你们会见到邮箱  上面的名字是格林
You'll see the mailbox, name's Greene.
驾
Hi-yah!
你丫闭嘴
Shut up.
中枪了
Shot?
什么叫"中枪了"
What do ya mean shot?
戴尔  我也不知道
I don't know, Dale.
我当时又不在
I wasn't there.
我只知道  她像佐罗一样骑着马突然出现
All I know is this chick rode out of nowhere like Zorro
然后把洛莉带走了
on a horse and took Lori.
你让她走了
You let her?
老兄  别鸡巴烦我
Climbed down out of my asshole, man.
是瑞克让她来的
Rick sent her.
她能叫出洛莉和卡尔的名字
She knew Lori's name and Carl's.
我听到尖叫声  是你吗
I heard screams, was that you?
有只行尸攻击她
She got attacked by a walker.
当时真是死里逃生啊
It was a close call.
安德莉亚  你没事吧
Andrea, are you all right?
这地方真美
This place is beautiful.
我们家族在此生活有一百六十年了
Been in my family 160 years.
真不敢相信它是如此安静
I can't believe how serene it is.
如此远离尘嚣
How untouched.
你们真幸运
You're lucky.
也不是人人都安然无恙
We weren't completely unscathed.
我们也失去了朋友  邻居
We lost friends, neighbors.
传染病夺走了我的妻子
The epidemic took my wife,
和继子
my stepson.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我的女儿们逃过一劫
My daughters were spared.
我为此感谢上帝
I'm grateful to god for that.
这里的这些人
These people here,
除了彼此便一无所有
all we've got left is each other.
只希望能平安度过难关
Just hoping we can ride it out in peace
直到找到解药
till there's a cure.
我们去过疾病防治中心
We were at the CDC...
现在那儿已经被夷为平地了
It's-it's gone now.
根本没有解药
There is no cure.
我不信
I don't believe it.
艾滋病出现时  大家都很恐慌
When AIDS came along, everyone panicked.
镇上有个男孩染病了
One boy in town came down with it,
一些家长就不让孩子去上学
and some parents pulled their children from school,
这样他们就不必坐在同一个教室里
so they didn't have to sit in the same room.
这完全是另一回事
This is a whole other thing.
人们总是这么说
That's what we always say.
"这次不同"
"This one's different."
这次确实是
Well, this one is.
人类自出现以来就在与各种传染病作斗争
Mankind's been fightin' plagues from the start.
我们曾处于被动挨打的局面
We get our behinds kicked for a while,
但又会重新站起
then, we bounce back.
这是自然界在自我修复
It's nature correcting herself,
恢复平衡
restoring some balance.
希望我能相信这套说法
I wish I could believe that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我的乖儿子
My baby boy.
乖儿子
Baby boy.
没事了
It's okay.
妈妈来了
Mama's here.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
我们会把你治好的
We're gonna make you okay.
慢点儿  慢点儿
Slow. Slow.
你输了几次血
How many transfusions?
两次  两次而已
Two. Only two.
你知道吗  当你在医院时
You know he wanted to do the same for you
他也想输血给你
when you were in the hospital.
我只好劝他打消这个念头
I had to talk him out of it.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的  我明白了
Okay, so I understand.
等肖恩和另一个人回来后
When Shane gets back with this other man--
-他叫奥蒂斯  -奥蒂斯
- Otis. - Otis.
那个开枪打我儿子的混蛋
The idiot who shot my son.
夫人  那只是个意外
Ma'am, it was an accident.
这事再说吧
I'll take that under advisement later.
目前来说他就是开枪打我儿子的混蛋
For now, he's the idiot who shot our son.
洛莉  他们现在正尽一切努力去补救
Lori, they're doing everything they can to make it right.
好吧  他们一回来
Okay, as soon as they get back
你就能进行手术吗
You can perform this surgery?
我肯定会尽我最大努力的
I'll certainly do my best.
好吧  我是说  你以前做过这个吗
Okay... I mean, you've done this procedure before?
从某种意义上来说  是的
Well, yes, in a sense.
从某种意义上
In a sense?
宝贝  我们没有时间
Honey, we don't have the luxury
去找另一个外科医生了
Of shopping for a surgeon.
我明白
No, I understand that.
但是我想知道  你是医生吧
But, I mean, you're a doctor, right?
是的  夫人  当然是
Yes, ma'am. Of course.
兽医
A vet.
老兵  是军医吗
A veteran-- a combat medic?
是兽医
A veterinarian.
你以前在什么东西上动过这种手术
And you've done this surgery before on what?
牛  猪
Cows... Pigs?
我得先坐下来
I-- I have-- I have to sit.
你疯了吧
Completely in over your head, aren't you?
夫人  我们不都是吗
Ma'am, aren't we all?
嘘
Shh-shh-shh!
好了  我们看一眼
okay, let's take a look.
你看到路对面那个大医疗拖车了吗
You see that big mobile medical trailer across the way?
那就是我们要去的地方吗
That's where we gotta get to?
对
Yeah.
我不能那么做
I won't do it.
我们不能这么离开
We can't just leave.
卡萝尔  队伍现在四分五裂
Carol, the group is split.
我们一盘散沙  只有挨打的份
We're scattered and weak.
如果她回来发现我们不在这儿怎么办
What if she comes back and we're not here?
有这个可能
It could happen.
如果索菲亚回来而我们已经走了
If sophia found her way back and we were gone,
那就糟糕了
That would be awful.
好吧
Okay.
我们得订个计划
We gotta plan for this.
要我说  明早动身就可以了
I say tomorrow morning is soon enough to pull up stakes.
这样可以留出些时间做标志
Give us a chance to rig a big sign,
给她留一些补给
Leave her some supplies.
我今天晚上就守在这儿  跟房车一起
I'll hold here tonight, stay with the rv.
如果房车留下  我也留下来
If the rv is stayin', I am too.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你们俩
Thank you both.
我也加入
I'm in.
如果你们都留下那么我
Well, if you're all staying then I'm--
你不要留下  格伦  你得去
Not you, glenn-- you're going.
开卡萝尔的切诺基走
Take-take Carol's cherokee.
我
Me?
为什么总是我
Why is it always me?
你必须找到农场  跟我们的人取得联系
You have to find this farm, reconnect with our people
看看情况如何  最重要的是
And see what's going on-- but most important,
你必须把T仔带到那儿
You have to get t-dog there.
没别的选择
This is not an option.
那个伤口在恶化
That cut has gone from bad to worse.
他还有严重的血液感染
He has a very serious blood infection.
把他送到农场去
Get him to that farm.
看他们有没有抗生素
See if they have any antibiotics.
如果没有的话T仔会死的  这不是玩笑
Because if not, t-dog will die, no joke.
把你的油抹布从我哥的摩托车上拿走
Keep your oily rags off my brother's motorcycle.
你为什么等到现在才说
Why'd you wait till now to say anything?
找到我哥的存货了
Got my brother's stash.
安非他命  不需要
Crystal, x-- don't need that.
找到一些强力止痛药
Got some kick ass painkillers.
脱氧土霉素
Doxycycline.
不是一般的东西
Not the generic stuff neither.
这可是上等的
It's first class.
莫尔有时候会得淋病
Merle got the clap on occasion.
血压又下降了
Pressure's dropping again.
我们不能再等了
We can't wait much longer.
再输点血  他需要多少都行
Take some more-- whatever he needs.
-然后我们走  -去哪
- Then I'm gonna go. - Go-- go where?
他说五英里
He said five miles.
他们现在应该回来了
They should be long back by now.
-有点不对劲  -你疯了吗
- Something's gone wrong. - Are you insane?
你不是去找他们
You're not goin' after them.
瑞克 听你妻子的
Rick, listen to your wife.
如果他们陷入麻烦
If they got into trouble--
你这状态根本帮不上忙
You're in no condition to do anything about it.
你被抽了很多血
You've given too much blood.
站都站不稳
You're barely on your feet.
你都没法穿过院子
You wouldn't make it across the yard.
肯定发生了意外  我必须去
Something happened, I have to go.
不行  你必须呆在这
No, your place is here.
如果肖恩说他会回来  他会回来的
If shane said he'll be back, he'll be back.
那方面他很像你
He's like you that way.
我没法坐这干等
I can't just sit here.
你必须这么做
That's exactly what you do!
如果你想祈祷或是痛哭
If you need to pray or cry
或者告诉上帝他太残忍  请便
Or tell god he's cruel, you go right ahead,
但是你不能走  瑞克
But you're not leavin', rick.
卡尔需要你  在这里
Carl needs you-- here.
我自己不行
and I can't do this by myself.
这次不行
Not this one.
我不能
I can't...
I can't.
在这里
Oh, here.
气管内插管器  宝贝
Endotracheal intubator, baby,
给新呼吸器配上
For my new respirator.
干得好
Atta boy!
快走
Come on.
-快走  -该死
- Come on! - Damn it.
-快点  -跟着我
- Come on. - Stay with me!
不要
No-- no-no-no-no!
快走
Come on!
不要
No-no-no-no!
快走  快走
Come on-- come on.
进来
In here!
好了  好了
Okay-okay!
退后  退后
Stay back-- stay back!
该死
Damn it!